Frank C. Laubach Collection
Frank C. Laubach Collection
- Languages
  - Kikongo, Belgian Congo, 2 folders (Box 273)
  - Kikuyu, Kenya, 2 folders (Box 274)
  - Kikuyu, Kenya (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Kikwango, Belgian Congo (Box 274)
  - Kimanga, Belgian Congo (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Kimbala, Belgian Congo (Box 274)
  - Kimbundu, Angola (Box 274)
  - Kirundi, Rwanda, Urundi (Box 274)
  - Kisi, Sierra Leone (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Kiswahili, Kenya (Box 274)
  - Kituba, Congo (Box 274)
  - Kiyanzi (Kimputu), Belgian Congo (Box 274)
  - Kono, Sierra Leone (Box 274)
  - Korean, Korea
    - I-II, 2 folders (Box 274)
    - III-IV, 2 folders (Box 275)
  - Kpelle, Liberia (Box 275)
  - Kru, Liberia (Box 275)
  - Kru, Sierra Leone (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Kuanua, New Guinea (Box 275)
  - Kuranko, Sierra Leone (Box 275)
  - Kuvi, India (Box 275)
  - Lahu, Burma (Box 275)
  - Laotian, Laos (Box 275)
  - Lesotho, South Africa (Box 276)
  - Limba, Sierra Leone (Box 276)
  - Lingala, Belgian Congo (Box 276)
  - Loekele, Belgian Congo (Box 276)
  - Loma, Liberia (Box 276)
  - Lomango, Lokundo, Congo (Box 276)
  - Lomue, Mozambique (Box 276)
  - Lozi [Zambia] (Box 276)
  - Luganda, Uganda (Box 276)
  - Lunda, Northern Rhodesia (Box 276)
  - Luo, Kenya (Box 276)
  - Mabea, Makae, French Cameroun (Box 276)
  - Luyia, Kenya (Box 276)
  - Malagasy, Magagascar (Box 276)
  - Malay, Singapore (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Malayalam, India (Box 277)
  - Mam, Guatemala Indian Philippines (Box 277)
  - Mampruli, Gold Coast (Ghana) (Box 277)
  - Mandarin, China (Box 277)
  - Mandingo, Sierra Leone (Box 277)
  - Mano, Liberia (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Manobo, Philippines (Box 277)
  - Maranaw, Philippines, 2 folders (Box 277)
  - Marathi, India, 2 folders (Box 277)
  - Masai, Kenya (Box 278)
  - Mayan, Mexico (Box 278)
  - Mazateco, Mexico (Box 278)
  - Medlpa, New Guinea (Box 278)
  - Mende, Sierra Leone (Box 278)
  - Mindanao, Philippines (Box 278)
  - Moro, Philippines (Box 278)
  - Moru, Sudan (Box 278)
  - Morung, Australia (Box 278)
  - Moto, Philippines (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Naga dialects, Asam, India (Box 278)
  - Nandi, Kenya (Box 278)
  - Navajo, U.S. Indian (Box 278)
  - Ndebele, Rhodesia (Box 278)
  - Nepali, Nepal, 2 folders (Box 279)
  - Nigeria (Box 279)
  - Niha, Tanganyika (Box 279)
  - Njanja, Zambia Nyasaland (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Olunyore, Kenya (Box 279)
  - Omampuli, Gold Coast (Box 279)
  - Oriya, India, 3 folders (Box 279)
  - Otetela, Congo (Box 279)
  - Oulof, French West Africa (Box 279)
  - Pangasinan, Philippines (Box 280)
  - Pangasinan, Philippines (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Parbatia, Nepal (Box 280)
  - Patua, Sierra Leone (Box 280)
  - Persian
    - Afghanistan (Box 280)
    - Iran (Box 280)
    - West Pakistan (Box 280)
  - Pidgin
    - Australia (Box 280)
    - New Guinea (Box 280)
  - Portuguese
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 280)
    - Angola (Box 280)
    - Brazil, 2 folders (Box 281)
    - Bi-lingual readers, Mozambique (Box 281)
    - Bi-lingual readers, Mozambique (oversize) (Box 294)
    - Portuguese literacy materials (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Punjabi
    - Pakistan (Box 281)
    - Persia (Box 281)
    - India (Box 281)
  - Purai, Papua New Guinea (Box 281)
  - Pushtu
    - Afghanistan (Box 281)
    - West Pakistan (Box 281)
  - Putu, Liberia (Box 281)
  - Pwo karen, Burma (Box 281)
  - Quechua
    - Bolivia, Ecuador, Guatemala (Box 282)
    - Peru (oversize) (Box 294)
  - Rimi, Tanganyika (Box 282)
  - Roro, Papua New Guinea (Box 282)
  - Rukuba, Nigeria (Box 282)
  - Samarino, Philippines (Box 282)
  - Sango, Chad (Box 282)
  - Santali, India (Box 282)
  - Saora, India (Box 282)
  - Sesotho, South Africa (oversize) (Box 294)
  - Sgaw karen, Burma (Box 282)
  - Shibukeni, Northern Rhodesia (Box 282)
  - Shona, Southern Rhodesia (Box 282)
  - Shona, Southern Rhodesia (oversize) (Box 294)
  - Sindebele, Southern Rhodesia (oversize) (Box 294)
  - Sindhi, Pakistan (Box 282)
  - Sinhalese, Ceylon (Box 282)
  - Spanish
    - [General] (Box 282)
    - [General] (Box 283)
    - Argentina (Box 283)
    - Bolivia (Box 283)
    - Chile (Box 283)
    - Colombia (Box 283)
    - Costa Rica, 2 folders (Box 283)
    - Costa Rica (Box 284)
    - Cuba (Box 284)
    - Cuba (oversize) (Box 294)
    - Dominican Republic (Box 284)
    - Ecuador (Box 284)
    - Film, Teaching Spanish for illiterate adults, script (Box 284)
    - General, 2 folders (Box 284)
    - General (oversize) (Box 294)
    - Guatemala (Box 285)
    - Jamaica (Box 285)
    - Jamaica (oversize) (Box 294)
    - Mexico, 2 folders (Box 285)
    - Mexico (oversize) (Box 294)
    - Peru (oversize) (Box 294)
    - Puerto Ric (Box 285)
    - Venezuela (oversize) (Box 294)
    - Word list (Box 285)
  - Swahili, Congo
    - General (Box 285)
    - General (Box 286)
    - Kenya, television (Box 286)
    - Ki-swahili, Congo (Box 286)
  - Swazi, Swaziland, 2 folders (Box 286)
  - Subano, Philippines (Box 286)
  - Tagalog, Philippines (Box 286)
  - Tagalog, Philippines (oversize) (Box 294)
  - Tamahaq, Sahara, Algeria (Box 286)
  - Tamil, India (Box 286)
  - Tamil, India (oversize) (Box 295)
  - Tamil (Romanized), India (Box 286)
  - Taung Thu, Burma (Box 287)
  - Tchien, Liberia (oversize) (Box 295)
  - Telugu, India (Box 287)
  - Telugu, India (oversize) (Box 295)
  - Temne, Sierra Leone (Box 287)
  - Terena, Portuguese, Brazil (Box 287)
  - Thadou kuki, Assam, India (Box 287)
  - Thai, Thailand (Box 287)
  - Tifinagh, Tamahaq (Box 287)
  - Tiv, Nigeria (Box 287)
  - Tonga (Box 287)
  - Tsetchuana, South Africa (Box 287)
  - Tshiluba, Congo (Box 287)
  - Tshwa, Transvaal (Box 287)
  - Tsongo, Mozambique (Box 287)
  - Turu, Tanganyika (Box 287)
  - Turkish (Box 287)
  - Turkish, Turkey (oversize) (Box 295)
  - Twende, Tanganyika (Box 287)
  - Umbundu, Angola (Box 288)
  - Urdu
    - India (Box 288)
    - West Pakistan, 1962-1963; 4 folders (Box 288)
    - West Pakistan, 1962-1963 (Box 289)
  - Urundi, Belgian Congo (Box 289)
  - Vai, Liberia (Box 289)
  - Venda, South Africa (Box 289)
  - Vietnamese (Box 289)
  - Vietnamese primer, original (Box 289)
  - Visayan, Philippines (Box 289)
  - Xhosa, South Africa (Box 289)
  - Xironga, Mozambique (Box 289)
  - Yiddish (Box 289)
  - Yoruba, Nigeria (Box 290)
  - Zande, Sudan (Box 290)
  - Zapotec, Mexico (Box 290)
  - Zeme naga, Assam (Box 290)
  - Zulu, South Africa (Box 290)
- Manuscripts and articles
  - Cornish, Louis C. "Philippines Calling, The", 1942 (Box 296)
  - Cortright, Richard
    - Articles, miscellaneous, 1955-1969 (Box 296)
    - "Literacy, U.S. A.", 1964 (Box 296)
    - "Readings in Literistics," I, 1961 (Box 296)
    - Speeches (Box 296)
    - "Training Volunteer Literacy Teachers", 1963 (Box 296)
  - Crow, Martha F. "Christ in the Poetry of To-day," excerpts from (Box 296)
  - Dames, J.J. "Christ's Message; a Harmony of the Four Gospels", 1970 (Box 296)
  - Duncan, Hall "How Africans See Pictures", 1962 (Box 296)
  - Encyclopedia of Education article (Box 296)
  - Ereno, Paz notes and essays (Box 297)
  - Fisher, Margaret notes and essays (Box 297)
  - Hagedorn, Hermann "Bomb that Fell on America", 1948 (Box 297)
  - Haynes, Evelyn "How to Introduce the Laubach Literacy Aids to the Foreign Students Studying in the United States.", 1961 (Box 297)
  - Hopkins, Maria "The True Spirit of Christmas" (Box 297)
  - Johnson, Raymond "Measurement and Classification of Teacher Attitudes Toward Illiterates" (Box 297)
  - King, Sidney E. "Christianity is Communism", 1961 (Box 297)
  - Laubach, Frank
    - "Christ Liveth in Me" original manuscripts, 1970 (Box 297)
    - "Christ Liveth in Me" (Box 297)
    - "Christian, You Can Save the World", 1968-1969 (Box 297)
    - "Compassion of Jesus As Told by Matthew" reformed story (Box 297)
    - "Did Mary Tell Jesus Her Secret?", undated (Box 297)
    - "Did Mary Tell Jesus Her Secret?", 1967; undated; 2 folders (Box 298)
    - Ch. I, 1968 (Box 298)
    - "English the New Way," explanation of, 2 folders (Box 298)
    - Foreign Reading Book manuscripts, 1943 (Box 298)
    - "Forty Years with the Silent Billion" (Box 299)
    - "Greatest Life, the", 1956 (Box 299)
    - "Greatest Life, the" draft (Box 299)
    - "Growing Bigger Every Day", 1961 (Box 299)
    - "Heavenly Ways of Earth's Graduates", 1962 (Box 299)
    - "How to Make the World Literate" draft (Box 299)
    - "How to Teach One and Win One for Christ" (Box 299)
    - "Key System of Teaching Illiterates", 1932 (Box 299)
    - "The Last Ten Years", 2 folders (Box 299)
    - "Learning the Vocabulary of God", 1908 (Box 299)
    - "Letters by a Modern Mystic" 2 folders, 1955 (Box 299)
    - "Making the World Literate" (Box 299)
    - Manuscripts, various (Box 299)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 299)
    - "Nations are Learning Compassion, the" (Box 300)
    - Pamphlets (Box 300)
    - "Positive Thing, the", 1970 (Box 300)
    - "Prayer, the Mightiest Force in the World", 1946; 2 folders (Box 300)
    - "Silent Billion Speak, the", 1945 (Box 300)
    - Spelling reform, 1948 (Box 300)
    - "Story of Jesus, the, Retold from the Bible" parts I-III, 1957 (Box 300)
    - "Streamlined English Lessons, Teachers Manual", 1946 (Box 300)
    - "Teaching Illiterates" (Box 300)
    - "Wake Up or Blow Up", 1957 (Box 301)
    - "War of Amazing Love" orig. manuscripts (Box 301)
    - "Was Jesus Really God's Son?", 1967 (Box 301)
    - "What Jesus Had to Say About Money", 1966 (Box 301)
    - "Why There are Vagrants; a Study", 1916 (Box 301)
    - "World is Learning Compassion, the" draft (Box 301)
  - Laubach, Robert
    - Articles, various (Box 301)
    - Dissertation, framework of, "Criteria for the Readability of Materials in English for Adults of Limited Reading Ability", 1961 (Box 301)
    - "Flight to Mount Hagen," Literacy Journal, 1947-1948 (Box 301)
    - "Lyceum and Chautauqua, Early Adult Education Experiments", 1955 (Box 302)
    - Notes (Box 302)
    - Reports and articles (Box 302)
  - Laubach, Robert and Cortright, Richard, "Readings in Literacy Education" (Box 302)
  - Literacy, world, articles re (Box 302)
  - Lowe, Lorenzo, essays and articles, various, 1961-1962 (Box 302)
  - Manuscript, German (Box 302)
  - Mason, David
    - Manuscript for book, Apostle to the Illiterates, 2 folders (Box 328C)
    - Notes (Box 302)
    - Miscellaneous, abstract, fragments, chapter from Ancient Literacy (Box 328C)
  - Morgan, Angela, manuscripts, various, 2 folders (Box 302)
  - Philippines (Box 302)
  - Roberts, Helen, "Dust or Destiny?" (Box 302)
  - Schultz, Minnie, "Anda Ka Swng" (Box 302)
  - Singh, Sundar Sadhu "With and Without Christ", 1929 (Box 302)
  - Spaulding, Seth, "How to Evaluate Your Educational Publication for New Literates", 1956 (Box 302)
  - Stafford, Virginia, 1967 (Box 303)
  - "Story of Jesus," Spanish Books I-XII, 1967 (Box 303)
  - Success Stories, 1967-1968 (Box 303)
  - Varmah, Evangeline (Box 303)
  - Vrooman, Carl, "A Free World Manifesto", 1966 (Box 303)
  - Whittington, Dick, "God's Gauntlet" (Box 303)
- Organizations and meetings
  - Adult Education Association, undated (Box 304)
  - Adult Education Association, 1960-1967; 5 folders (Box 304)
  - Adult Basic Education, Adult Education Association (Box 304)
  - Adult Education
    - ERIC Clearinghouse, 1967 (Box 304)
    - National seminars, 1968 (Box 304)
  - Aerospace Industries Association of America, Inc., 1964 (Box 304)
  - Afghanistan: International Afghanistan Mission, 1966-1967 (Box 304)
  - African Enterprise, 1969 (Box 304)
  - American Associations of Evangelical Studies, Inc., 1966 (Box 304)
  - American Council on Education, Forty-Sixth Annual Meeting, 1963 (Box 304)
  - American Farm School, Greece, 1960-1961 (Box 304)
  - American Library Association, 1965-1968 (Box 304)
  - American Voluntary Agencies, 1962 (Box 304)
  - Amigos de las Americas, Inc., 1965-1966 (Box 304)
  - Arden House Program, Columbia University, 1964-1968 (Box 304)
  - Arms of Friendship, 1961 (Box 304)
  - Asgrow Seed Company, 1966 (Box 304)
  - Associations, various, 1963-1968 (Box 304)
  - Baptist Church, 1961-1968 (Box 305)
  - Baptist General Convention (Box 305)
  - Books for the People Fund, Inc., 1962-1965; 4 folders (Box 305)
  - Business International (Box 305)
  - Campbell Folk School (Box 305)
  - Camps Farthest Out, 1961-1969; undated; 5 folders (Box 305)
  - Canadian Association for Adult Education, 1964 (Box 305)
  - C.A.R.E.
    - Undated (Box 305)
    - 1960-1962, 1967; 2 folders (Box 306)
  - Christian Youth Corps of America, Inc. (Box 306)
  - Church World Service, 1966-1967 (Box 306)
  - CIHU (Box 306)
  - Committee on Adult Education, 1965 (Box 306)
  - Committee on World Literacy (Box 306)
  - Community Action Program, 1965 (Box 306)
  - Conferences, miscellaneous, 1960-1969; 3 folders (Box 306)
  - Conferences, general (Box 306)
  - Council of the Southern Mountains, 1967 (Box 306)
  - Education, White House Conference on, 1965 (Box 306)
  - Evangelical Literature Overseas, 1967 (Box 306)
  - Evangelism, World Conference on, 2 folders (Box 306)
  - Foundation for World Literacy
    - Undated (Box 306)
    - Undated (Box 307)
    - 1955-1963, 3 folders (Box 307)
  - Freedom from Hunger Foundation, Inc., 1966 (Box 307)
  - Freedom Reaching Everyone Everywhere (Box 307)
  - Graham, Billy, Evangelistic Association, 1970 (Box 307)
  - Illiteracy, World Conference on (Box 307)
  - Indianapolis Literacy Institute, Indiana University, 1961 (Box 307)
  - Inter-American Literacy Foundation, 1962 (Box 307)
  - International Communications, Council on, 1970 (Box 307)
  - International Education Institute, 1962-1963 (Box 307)
  - International Institute of San Francisco (Box 307)
  - International Service Organization (Box 307)
  - International Voluntary Services, Inc., 1963-1964 (Box 307)
  - International Youth Leadership Training Course, 1965-1966 (Box 307)
  - Involvement, Inc. (Box 307)
  - Journalism, Association for Education in, 1966 (Box 307)
  - Koinonia Foundation
    - [General], 4 folders (Box 308)
    - 1957-1968, 2 folders (Box 308)
    - 1961-1970, 5 folders (Box 309)
    - "Awake" Koinonia Co-workers' newsletter (Box 309)
    - "Epistle to the Koinonians", 2 folders (Box 309)
    - "Koinonia Magazine", 2 folders (Box 310)
    - "Koinonia Partner Report" (Box 310)
    - "World Newssheet" (Box 310)
  - Laymen's Movement for a Christian World, Inc. (Box 310)
  - Laymen Overseas (Box 310)
  - Leadership Resources, Inc., 1963 (Box 310)
  - League of Women Voters (Box 310)
  - Le Moyne College International House, 1964-1966 (Box 310)
  - Library of Congress, 1955 (Box 310)
  - Literacy Action Foundation (Box 310)
  - Literacy Evangelism, Inc.
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 310)
    - Rice, Robert F., 1967-1968 (Box 310)
  - Literacy Organization, Colombia (Box 310)
  - Manpower Training, Inc., 1967 (Box 310)
  - Meals for Millions, Inc. (Box 310)
  - Mennonite Central Committee (Box 310)
  - Missionary Society of the Congregational Christian Churches, 1963 (Box 310)
  - National Association for Public School Adult Education (NAPSAE)
    - 1956-1968 (Box 310)
    - 1963 (Box 311)
  - National Association of Congregational Christian Churches, 1964 (Box 311)
  - National Broadcasting Company publications, 1968 (Box 311)
  - National Citizens Committee for Broadcasting, 1969 (Box 311)
  - National Council of Teachers of English, 1964 (Box 311)
  - National Education Association (Box 311)
  - National Service Conference (Box 311)
  - New World Foundation, 1954-1961 (Box 311)
  - New York Author's League (Box 311)
  - Operation Alphabet, 1962-1963 (Box 311)
  - Organizations, general (Box 311)
  - Pan-American Union, 1963-1965 (Box 311)
  - Pan-American Union Library Development Program, 1965 (Box 311)
  - People to People, 1956-1965; 1957 (Box 311)
  - Plymouth Youth Center, 1965-1966 (Box 311)
  - Project Concern in Mexico, 1969 (Box 311)
  - Reading Reform, Foundation, 1970 (Box 311)
  - Red Cross (Box 311)
  - Religious Heritage of America, Inc. (Box 311)
  - Resources, U.S.A. (Box 311)
  - Retired Persons, American Association of (AARP) (Box 311)
  - Salvation Army, 1965-1969 (Box 312)
  - Science Research Associates, Inc., 1967 (Box 312)
  - Social Welfare Assembly, 1966 (Box 312)
  - Society for International Development, 1960-1961 (Box 312)
  - Southern Baptist Project (Box 312)
  - Southwest Community House Association, 1963-1964 (Box 312)
  - UNESCO, 1960-1967 (Box 312)
  - United Methodist Church (Box 312)
  - United Nations, 1949-1964 (Box 312)
  - Urban League, Washington, D.C., 1967 (Box 312)
  - Vocational Education Project, Draper, 1963 (Box 312)
  - Voluntary Foreign Relief Program, 1961 (Box 312)
  - Voluntary Organizations for Foreign Service, Inc., 1968 (Box 312)
  - Washington Program for Laymen Overseas, 1966 (Box 312)
  - Wilmington Legislative Committee, 1962 (Box 312)
  - Wingspread Conference, 1966 (Box 312)
  - World Literacy and Christian Literature, Committee on, 1961-1963 (Box 313)
  - World Literacy by Television Conference (Box 313)
  - World Literacy Evangelism, Inc. (Box 313)
  - World Neighbors, Inc. (Box 313)
  - Y.W.C.A.: Teaching Literacy, 1965 (Box 313)
- Miscellaneous
  - Clippings
    - I-IV, 5 folders (Box 314)
    - VI-XI, 6 folders (Box 315)
    - XII-XVI, 5 folders (Box 316)
    - XVII-XXII, 6 folders (Box 317)
    - XXIII-XXVII, 5 folders (Box 318)
    - XXVIII-XXXII, 5 folders (Box 319)
    - XXXIII-XXXVIII, 6 folders (Box 320)
  - Information, miscellaneous (Box 321)
  - Information booklets, various (Box 321)
  - Leaders, world, lists of (Box 321)
  - Newsletters
    - I-VI, 6 folders (Box 321)
    - VII-XII, 6 folders (Box 322)
    - XIII (Box 323)
  - Newsletters, foreign (Box 323)
  - Plays (Box 323)
  - Poems
    - General (Box 323)
    - Morgan, Angela (Box 323)
  - Prayers
    - General (Box 323)
    - Hopkins, Maria (Box 323)
  - Printed matter (Box 323)
  - Programs, miscellaneous (Box 323)
  - Songs (Box 323)
  - Records (Box 323)
- Photographs
  - Chile (Box 324)
  - Afghanistan (Box 324)
  - Africa, 2 folders (Box 324)
  - Africa, Katanga, Jadotville, 1961 (Box 324)
  - Africa, Tripoli (Box 324)
  - Art work (Box 324)
  - Audio-visual materials (Box 324)
  - Bolivia (Box 324)
  - Burma (Box 324)
  - Camps Farthest Out (Box 324)
  - "Chains" (Box 324)
  - China (Box 324)
  - Colombia I (Box 324)
  - Colombia II-IV, 3 folders (Box 325)
  - Colombia prisons (Box 325)
  - Companies of Compassion (Box 325)
  - Ecuador (Box 325)
  - England (Box 325)
  - Ghana (Box 325)
  - Guatemala (Box 325)
  - Haiti (Box 325)
  - Hawaii (Box 325)
  - Honduras (British) (Box 325)
  - Hong Kong (Box 325)
  - India
    - [General] (Box 325)
    - Edwards, Fern (Box 325)
    - Bihar (Box 325)
    - Karthicappally (Box 325)
  - Indochina (Box 325)
  - Internal organizations I, II, 2 folders (Box 325)
  - Internal organizations III (Box 326)
  - Japan (Box 326)
  - Jordan (Box 326)
  - Katanga, Congo (Box 326)
  - Kenya (Box 326)
  - Kenya Literacy Mission, 1965 (Box 326)
  - Kenya Literacy Mission, 1965 (Box 328B)
  - Kuwait (Box 326)
  - Latin America, general (Box 326)
  - Laubach family, 2 folders (Box 326)
  - Laubach, Frank, 2 folders (Box 326)
  - Liberia, Monrovia (Box 326)
  - McMillan, May (Box 326)
  - Mexico I (Box 326)
  - Mexico II-III, 2 folders (Box 327)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Box 327)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified, "for book" (Box 328B)
    possibly for Mason's book, Apostle to the Illiterates
  - New Guinea (Box 327)
  - Nicaragua (Box 327)
  - Nigeria (Box 327)
  - Pakistan (Box 327)
  - Paraguay (Box 327)
  - Peace Corps, Colombia, 2 folders (Box 327)
  - Peace Corps, Colombia Literacy project (Box 328B)
  - Philippines (Box 327)
  - Rhodesia (Box 327)
  - Sudan (Box 327)
  - Taiwan (Box 327)
  - Thailand (Box 327)
  - Turkey (Box 327)
  - United States
    - Arizona (Box 327)
    - Arkansas (Box 327)
    - California (Box 327)
    - General, 4 folders (Box 328)
    - Kansas, 1965 (Box 328)
    - Kentucky (Box 328)
    - Louisiana (Box 328)
    - Michigan (Box 328)
    - Mississippi (Box 328)
    - Missouri (Box 328)
    - New Mexico (Box 328)
    - New York (Box 328)
    - Oklahoma (Box 328)
    - Oregon (Box 328)
    - Students, foreign (Box 328)
    - Tennessee (Box 328)
    - Texas (Box 328)
    - Washington, D. C. (Box 328)
    - Washington State (Box 328)
- Streamlined Reading Series Kinescope reels, 99 reels, each 29 minutes
  - Streamlined Reading #1 (Reel 1)
    Introduce books; welcome by Dr. Laubach; learn letters A-L; practice writing in simple words and sentences.
  - Streamlined Reading #7 (Reel 2)
    Lesson 3; introduce R, S, T, V, W, Y; use them in words and sentences, then write words.
  - Streamlined Reading #8 (Reel 3)
    Review charts #2 and #3; practice writing letters in book.
  - Streamlined Reading #13 (Reel 4)
    Introduce Z, A, E, I, 0, U; use in words and sentences; demonstrate how to write these letters, and write words using them.
  - Streamlined Reading #26 (Reel 5)
    Using Lesson 2 in book, y endings on words are explored; then these endings are used in sentences which are written in workbook.
  - Streamlined Reading #24 (Reel 6)
    Importance of sounds in word building; putting basic sounds together to form words.
  - Streamlined Reading #30 (Reel 7)
    Miss Helen Brown uses the Laubach method to review vowel sounds and then inserts them in monosyllabic words.
  - Streamlined Reading #32 (Reel 8)
    Review of Lessons 1-3; fill in blanks in sentences using words from lists and story.
  - Streamlined Reading #27 (Reel 9)
    Miss Helen Brown practices writing sentences using word groups "This is a ," insert simple adjectives and adverbs.
  - Streamlined Reading #25 (Reel 10)
    Miss Helen Brown reviews vowel sounds; then spells words the way they sound; and then spells them properly and uses them in sentences. For use with blue book.
  - Streamlined Reading #11 (Reel 11)
    Sentences, questions; practice reading in rhythm, natural breaks; practices writing T, P, N, H, K, W, S, F, R, B, L
  - Streamlined Reading #12 (Reel 12)
    Manuscript and cursive writing; practice writing to music; small b, f, t, r, y, p, d, h, n, v, g, j
  - Streamlined Reading #14 (Reel 13)
    Review of Lesson 3; Chart 4; sounds of Z and vowels; practice.
  - Streamlined Reading #15 (Reel 14)
    Practice writing capital letters to music; J, K, L, M, N, P, R, S, T, V, W, Y.
  - Streamlined Reading #10 (Reel 15)
    Reading and writing practice from Chart 2 and Chart 3; the sounds Sh, J, K, M, N; Chart 3, R, S, etc., to end of alphabet.
  - Streamlined Reading #9 (Reel 16)
    Writing practice from Chart 2; introduce last part of alphabet.
  - Streamlined Reading #16 (Reel 17)
    Chart 5, end of Book 1; last two letters, x and q; the sounds sh, th, ch, and wh.
  - Streamlined Reading #1A (Reel 18)
    Review Chart 1; practice writing letters A-L.
  - Streamlined Reading #5 (Reel 19)
    Review of sounds in Charts 1 and 2; practice writing letters in Chart 2; capitals and small letters B through P.
  - Streamlined Reading #2 (Reel 20)
    Review consonants B through H; practice writing consonants; some pictures; only one demonstration showing how to write small letters and capital letters.
  - Streamlined Reading #21 (Reel 21)
    Review Chart 1; introduce Chart 2; practice writing the letters.
  - Streamlined Reading #6 (Reel 22)
    Practice writing letters to music.
  - Streamlined Reading #3 (Reel 23)
    Practice writing letters using guidelines.
  - Streamlined Reading #22 (Reel 24)
    Reading in Book 2; Lesson 1; sound of i.
  - Streamlined Reading #20 (Reel 25)
    Practice with z and combinations qu, th, and wh; review sentences; questions, who, where; reading the alphabet; saying and writing alphabet.
  - Streamlined Reading #24 (Reel 26)
    Writing X and Q to music; writing numbers 2, 3, 4, 5; sentences written about pictures shown.
  - Streamlined Reading #21 (Reel 27)